PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Before switching career to web development, I have more than 3-years' professional experience in the migration industry, specialising in accounting skills assessment and individual migration. During my time with Coder Academy, I was able to plan, design, implement and deploy several applications from scratch to final products. As a developer, I look forward to combining my multi-disciplined domain knowledge and strong programming skills to help people achieve their goals in life through technology.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Aussie Beauty Market

https://aussie-beauty-market.herokuapp.com/

- Two-sided marketplace website on Ruby on Rails for trading second-hand makeup in Australia.
- E-commerce application, restful API, user authentication & authorisation, simple & advanced search capabilities, payment processing function, Q&A section and responsive web design.

Portfolio Website

https://elliechen.netlify.com/

- Portfolio website to showcase my web development skills and to demonstrate my professional experiences, transferable skills, personal projects, interests and personality.
- Different CSS/JavaScript effects on every webpage, fixed navigation bar and social icons bar, accessibility, sub-resource integrity and responsive web design.

Oriental Zodiac Patronus

https://github.com/EllieChen-Git/Oriental-Zodiac-Patronus

- Terminal application on Ruby to promote the Chinese horoscope (Chinese zodiac animals) to general public. Also serves as a fun and interactive educational game with family and friends.
- Chinese Zodiac Animal Test (find out your Chinese zodiac animal), Animal Compatibility Test (find out your perfect and worst matched zodiac animals) and Tai Sui Test (luck prediction in 2020).

SKILLS

TECH STACKS

- Programming Languages: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and SASS.
- Dependencies: Git, GitHub, AWS (S3 & IAM), deployment platforms (Heroku, Netlify), payment processing (Stripe), wireframe (Balsamiq) and sub-resource Integrity hash (sha-512).

LANGUAGES

NAATI Accredited Professional Interpreter (Mandarin and English).

EMPLOYMENT

Migration Coordinator/Migration Executive

Aug 2016 - Aug 2019

Chartered Accountants Australia & New Zealand (Sydney, Australia)

- Conducting migration assessment with high attention to details and identifying training needs.
- Interpreting the latest legislation changes and advising on difficult migration assessment issues.
- Proven time-management skills in handling high volumes of applications, prioritising tasks, meeting deadlines, and working autonomously and cooperatively in a high-performing professional team.

Assistant Migration Consultant

Sep 2014 - Jul 2016

Ausky Visa Solutions (Sydney, Australia)

- Efficiently managing a client's visa application from the initial engagement, eligibility assessment, follow-up correspondence, application lodgement to final decision, with a 95% visa approval rate.
- Effectively facilitating the communication between the mandarin-speaking clients and other English-speaking parties, including Immigration case officers and skills assessing authorities.

Localisation Project Manager and Translator

Jul 2010 - Jun 2011

Weasto Translation Company (Taipei, Taiwan)

- Intelligently organising translation projects, conducting human resource deployment of inhouse/freelance translators and editors, and liaising with international clients and local vendors.
- Effectively managing a one-million-words Expedia.com project and achieving scheduled goals.

EDUCATION

Diploma in Information Technology/Full-time Fast-track Bootcamp

Coder Academy (Sydney, Australia)

Aug 2019 – Mar 2020 (expected)

Graduate Certificate in Australian Migration Law and Practice (High Distinction Average)

The Australian National University (Canberra, Australia)

May 2017 – Nov 2017

Graduate Diploma in Professional Accounting (High Distinction Average)

Victoria University (Sydney, Australia)

Jul 2015 – Apr 2016

Postgraduate Diploma of Translating and Interpreting (Distinction Average)

Macquarie University (Sydney, Australia)

Aug 2014 – Jul 2015

Master of Translation and Interpreting (Later transferred to Macquarie University)

National Taiwan Normal University (Taipei, Taiwan)

Sep 2013 – Jun 2014

Bachelor of Arts with Major in English Literature (GPA: 3.72/4.00.)

National Chengchi University (Taipei, Taiwan)

Sep 2006 – Jun 2010

REFEREES

Available upon request.